Preliminary Guide to the Claire Keyes Papers, 1985-2009 RL.00776
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Claire Keyes papers
1985-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Keyes, Claire
RL.00776
3 Linear Feet
Claire Keyes was the executive director of the Allegheny Reproductive Health Center in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Accession (2009-0229) (3.0 lin. ft.; 1875 items; dated 1985-2009) includes: Allegheny Reproductive Health Center clinic files; National Coalition of Abortion Providers materials; National Abortion Federation meeting materials; NARAL guidelines and publications; newspaper articles; clinic insurance information; anti-abortion lawsuits, correspondence, threats, and arrests; spirituality counseling and other initiatives; and miscellaneous administrative information about the clinic. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
1875 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Claire Keyes Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Historical Note
Claire Keyes was the executive director of the Allegheny Reproductive Health Center in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.
Collection Overview
Accession (2009-0229) (3.0 lin. ft.; 1875 items; dated 1985-2009) includes: Allegheny Reproductive Health Center clinic files; National Coalition of Abortion Providers materials; National Abortion Federation meeting materials; NARAL guidelines and publications; newspaper articles; clinic insurance information; anti-abortion lawsuits, correspondence, threats, and arrests; spirituality counseling and other initiatives; and miscellaneous administrative information about the clinic.
Collection Arrangement
This collection has not been processed or arranged at this time. Materials are available in their original order with folders labelled by the donor.
Pro-life movement -- Pennsylvania; Pro-choice movement -- Pennsylvania; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Abortion -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Abortion -- Pennsylvania; Abortion services; National Coalition of Abortion Providers; National Abortion Rights Action League; Keyes, Claire; National Abortion Federation (U.S.); Allegheny Reproductive Health Center; Keyes, Claire
- Accession (2009-0229), 5 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Accession (2009-0229) (3.0 lin. ft.; 1875 items; dated 1985-2009) includes Allegheny Reproductive Health Center clinic files; National Coalition of Abortion Providers materials; National Abortion Federation meeting materials; NARAL guidelines and publications; newspaper articles; clinic insurance information; anti-abortion lawsuits, correspondence, threats, and arrests; spirituality counseling and other initiatives; and miscellaneous administrative information about the clinic.
  - National Coalition of Abortion Providers, Fall 2004 (Box 1)
  - National Abortion Federation, 2001 (Box 1)
  - National Abortion Federation, 2000 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - My Interviews, 1994-2008 (Box 1)
  - National Abortion Federation, 1999 (Box 1)
  - National Abortion Federation Plan, 1999 (Box 1)
  - National Coalition of Abortion Providers, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - National Coalition of Abortion Providers, 1998 Roe Event (Box 1)
  - National Abortion Federation Counseling, 1998 (Box 1)
  - National Abortion Federation, 1998 (Box 1)
  - National Abortion Federation, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Independent Providers, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Preparation for National Abortion Federation, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Roe, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Roe Event, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Safety of Abortion & Lime 5 Response (Box 1)
  - National Abortion Federation, 1997 (Box 2)
  - National Coalition of Abortion Providers Meeting, October 1996 (Box 2)
  - National Coalition of Abortion Providers Conference, 1996 (Box 2)
  - National Abortion Federation Planning, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Pittsburgh Phone Numbers, 1986-1994 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Articles Wichita, August 1991 (Box 2)
  - Local Articles, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Local Articles, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Articles on Arson, 6 September 1989 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Articles, January 1992 (Box 2)
  - Local Articles, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Other Articles, 1989 (Box 2)
  - News Articles-Jury Trial, April 1990 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Articles-Rearrests, 1988 (Box 2)
  - News Articles & National Anti Activities, 1989-1993 (Box 2)
  - Articles on incident, 17 June 1989 (Box 2)
  - Rescue Articles, Lambs for Christ, 12 July 1990 (Box 2)
  - Christian Liberation Army (Box 2)
  - Colonna Hearing, March 1992 (Box 2)
  - Lawsuits against Anti's, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Court Invasion, Police Report, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Photos of Anti's, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Opinion Articles, 1986-1989 (Box 2)
  - Local Articles, 1986-1988 (Box 2)
  - Abortion Terrorism, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Arrests from October 1989 Activity (Box 2)
  - Information on Rescue, Arrests, 30 September 1989 (Box 2)
  - Local Articles, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Arrest Lists, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Arrests, January-March 1989 (Box 3)
  - Arrests, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Arrests, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Anti's Arrested, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Woman Wanted for Arson (may picket clinic), 1988 (Box 3)
  - Information on Judy Dick, Mark Nelson, & Nancy McNulty (Box 3)
  - Articles on David Gunn, March 1993 (Box 3)
  - Tucci, Late 1980s-Early 1990s (Box 3)
  - Jamie Tellier, Van Hager, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Schmeidicke/Cleary Pardons 1991-1995 (Box 3)
  - News Articles L. Johnson Imposter, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Slepian, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Anti's literature, 1985-1994 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous: Glamour, DVD, etc. (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous: Internal clinic forms, 1990s (Box 3)
  - Notes for vision and speeches, 1990s (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Malpractice and abortion providers (Box 3)
  - Men and abortions, 2008 (Box 3)
  - Religion in America, 1998 (Box 3)
  - National Abortion Federation spiritual, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Letters of support re: fire and others, 1989 (Box 3)
  - 25th anniversary, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Strategic Plan, 1996-2000 (Box 3)
  - NARAL Advisory, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Specialty Wiking-after roof damage, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Reliable Corporation, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Fire Insurance File, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Minors, 2009 (Box 4)
  - National Abortion Federation notes, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Picker/Kaiser report, 1999 (Box 4)
  - NAF Insurance providers, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Impetus for chart change nationally, 1997 (Box 4)
  - FACE Act, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Photos, 1990s-2000s (Box 4)
  - Notepad of notes, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Medical meetings, 1997-1998 (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Medical meeting, 2007 (Box 4)
  - Survey results, undated (Box 4)
  - November Gang: Northland Family Planning Centers, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Clinic administration workshop, 1990s (Box 4)
  - New paradigm for multicultural counseling, 1999-2001 (Box 4)
  - Counseling aids/info, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Kisner-Empathetic conversation training, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Common Ground, 2001 (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - From your future patients, Letters from women in Abortion Facilities, 2004 (spiral) (Box 4)
  - Levels of counseling, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Jewish prayer after miscarriage (Box 4)
  - RCRC Pastoral counseling, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Borderline personality, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Medical meeting, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Judicial bypass proceedings, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Futurists, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Spiritual needs seminar, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Shostak: men and abortions surveys, 1999 (Box 4)
  - NCAP Annual Membership Conference, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Feminist Memorial Service (Box 4)
  - Counseling survey, 2000 (Box 4)
  - PA Dept. of Health STD testing, 2001 (Box 4)
  - NCAP 2003 (Box 4)
  - Special Session, June 10 2000 (Box 4)
  - Lesbian Healthcare (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous publications/ephemera, 1990s (Box 5)
  - Father Frank Pavone, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Escort information, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Projects archive, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Predisposing factors (Box 5)
  - Virtual Sanctuary, 2006 (Box 5)
  - Spirituality workshop, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Sanctuary, 2008 (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Dennis Roddy, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Women: Post-traumatic stress disorder, 2004 (Box 5)
  - Spirituality sessions, NCAP, 2002 (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania abortion providers, 2000s (Box 5)
- Accession (2012-0061), 3 boxes
  Accession (2012-0061) (1.4 lin. ft.; 900 items; dated 2000-2011) includes research on men and abortion; spirituality counseling and other initiatives; information about the Abortion in Translation project and a copy of the VHS; speeches and articles by Keyes; Keyes's notepads; correspondence; and a scrapbook from Keyes's retirement.
  - Clippings (Box 6)
  - Grant Apps (Box 6)
  - Notepads of notes (Box 6)
  - Speeches: Medical Students for Choices (MS4C) (Box 6)
  - Speeches: Law School 9/05 (Box 6)
  - Heartssite 2 (Box 6)
  - Medical Translation Project (Box 6)
  - Translation DVDs (Box 6)
  - Shostak Stats '00, Stats '04 (Box 6)
  - Abortion and Spirituality (Box 6)
  - Men and Abortion (Box 6)
  - Religious Coalition for Reproductive Choice (Box 6)
  - Religious survey - staff (Box 6)
  - FP and abortion clinics (Box 6)
  - Patient Survey (Box 6)
  - RCRC/Spiritual (Box 6)
  - Men and Abortion, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Men (Box 6)
  - For Seminary Proposal (Box 6)
  - National Abortion Federation Annual Meeting Syllabus, 2009 (Box 7)
  - Editorials and Interviews (Box 7)
  - Workshop on Abortion and Spirituality, 2008 (Box 7)
  - Claire's contributions to women's history (Box 7)
  - Letter to editor (Box 7)
  - TAWG (Training and Access Work Group) (Box 7)
  - Allegheny Reproductive Health Center (Box 7)
  - Men's Survey (Box 7)
  - Language Videos - Order Form and Labels (Box 7)
  - Mailing (Box 7)
  - Master Copies Language Tapes (Box 7)
  - womenstories Brochures, Allegheny Reproductive Health Center (Box 7)
  - Bottom Feeder (Box 7)
  - David Gunn Tribute, National Coalition of Abortion Providers (Box 7)
  - Second Trimester Pregnancy Termination Referrals out of State, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Minors petition to court (Box 7)
  - For Men: Before and After Abortion by Ann Baker (Box 7)
  - Abortion Care Network Newsletter, 2009 (Box 7)
  - Abortion in Translation VHS (Box 7)
  - Sacred Choices and Abortion: 10 New Things to Think About DVD (Box 7)
  - "The Evolution of an Abortion Clinic, 1978-2008" DVD (Box 7)
  - Award plaque, Abortion Conversation Project, 2006 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook (Box 8)